Brooklyn, New York

Sculptor, media scholar, and educator turned full stack developer, with over five years of experience developing websites and digital design for businesses ranging from e-commerce to educational institutions. I take an interdisciplinary approach to interactive media and computer networking technology. My other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and making generative sound objects.

## **Technical Skills**

- · Full Stack Web Development Flask, React, Vue S, Frontend Frameworks, Postgres, Mongodb
- · Operations \*NIX System Administration, Git, Heroku, Cloud Providers, Docker, Squid, Wireshark
- · Creative Coding Processing, P5JS, Open Frameworks, Glitch, D3JS
- Programming Languages Bash, Javascript, Node JS, Python, Go, C
- · Hardware Raspberry Pi, Arduino, ESP8266
- Digital Accessibility Standards WCAG 2.1, Section 508

## **Professional Experience**

2015- MARK OF THE LAM

Freelance Developer, New York City, Ho Chi Minh City, Los Angeles, Berkeley

- Design and develop websites for business ranging from personal artists to independent publishing houses to promote
  products, events and services with clients located in Israel, Qatar, Hong Kong, and United States
- · Implement features such as REST API's and online payment procedures to streamline development time
- · Scope timelines and specifications while coordinating with clients to meet business objectives
- · Work with account managers to deploy websites to production, to troubleshoot bugs and errors

2019-2020

New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Coding Lab Mentor, New York City

- Provided code tutoring for NYU students across NYU's campuses and departments
- Supported students in project ideation and technical development
- Helped faculty to identify students needs to provide additional support
- Led tutorial workshops for introductory computer programming

2018-2020

New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer, New York City

- Developed an accessibility compliant front-end interface for a project database to meet NYU accessibility initiative guidelines in accordance to WCAG standards
- $\bullet \ \ Created \ training \ materials \ to \ conduct \ accessibility \ audits \ with \ assistive \ tech \ including \ VoiceOver, \ Jaws, \ and \ Lighthouse/WAVE$
- Mentored and trained students in web accessible programming paradigms so students will consider impact of
  accessibility in their development career
- Collaborated with UX designers and faculty to create educational materials and data visualization

2018-2019

LINCOLN CENTER FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS Digital Accessibility Fellow, New York City

- Created internal digital accessibility training material for engineering and legal departments to promote access for a diverse customer base
- Created an automated work process for captioning a catalog of over 1000 hours of video content
- Audited internal and external digital media of a world-class performing arts institution and write recommendations to meet WCAG 2.1 and Section 508 compliance
- Prototype a fully compliant digital map of campus accessibility features to simplify wayfinding

2017-2018

Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology & Education Visiting Lecturer – Introductory Programming, English, Ho Chi Minh City

- Developed an introductory English/programming curriculum in the C language for non-native English speaking engineering students, and worked with student leaders to promote extracurricular English study
- · Led supplemental workshops in specialized programming topics such as web design and portfolio building

## Education

May 2020 Interactive Telecommunications, Master of Professional Studies

New York University, New York City

Dec 2015 Media Studies & Art Practice, Bachelor of Arts

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

May 2013 Graphic Design, Associate of Arts

College of the Canyons, Valencia

## **Projects & Workshops**

2020 Bridge to the Internet, Website, Open Source Software, Computer Networking

NYU ITP, New York City

· Open Source router configuration built on Raspberry Pi

· Website built with Vue.js explaining computer networking topics

2020 Automating Mindfully, Technical Workshop

Unconference at ITP NYU, New York City

- · Introduction to Bash scripting language for beginner coders and introduce automation as meditative practice
- Explore automation as a meditative practice

2019 Network Operator, Performance

NIME 2019, New York City

- Created a system of 9 networked Raspberry Pi's to create a percussive instrument
- · Developed custom servers to trigger motors based on network activity

2019 Lincoln Center Campus Accessibility Map, Digital Map

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, New York City

- · Created a digital map of the Lincoln Center Campus that is fully compliant to WCAG 2.1 standards
- Extended Google Maps API to incorporate WAI-ARIA features